Mss.973.314.L95 Mss.973.314.L95
American Philosophical Society
Papers of American Loyalists, 1782-1798
Mss.973.314.L95
American Philosophical Society
10.0 Item(s)
There are letters, petitions, and reports concerning the Loyalists and the losses they sustained in the Revolutionary War. Includes the Committee of American Merchants, Observations on trade (1783), Banished American merchants petition (1789), and Classes of American loyalists and their claims.
10 items.
Box-folder 1
Early American History Note
The Loyalist Collection contains ten documents that pertain to the interests and affairs of American Loyalists after the American Revolution. The items convey the grievances of Loyalists, particularly merchants. The documents of relate to how the states treated Loyalists and their property after the Revolution. Most of the documents are either official government documents or formal reports. Reports by the Committee of American Merchants, a Loyalists group that formed in Britain after the war, are included as are records relating to the disposition of Penn family interests in Pennsylvania. Also of note is a multi-page, loose-leaf list of loyalists and their claims on the British treasury for services rendered during the war.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Purchased and accessioned, 1958 (1958 1538ms).
American loyalists.; American Revolution; Colonial Politics; Commerce.; Government Affairs; Land and Speculation; Legal Records; Official Government Documents and Records; Petitions.; Political Correspondence; Reports.; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Personal histories.
- Papers
  - Letter to Thomas Townshend, Nov. 16, 1782; 12-1/4x8; Dorchester, Guy Carleton, Baron, 1724-1808
    Scope and Contents note
    New York, L. 4p.and end. Copy. (see Loyalist... Material; 1782-1798.) Concerning Washington's attempt to entice Loyalists back to his side.
  - Observations on the trade of North America, July 22, 1783; 16-1/2 x 11; Loyalist American merchants
    D.S.: Edw[ar]d Payne. 10p.and end. (see Loyalist... Material; 1782-1798.)
  - An act repealing two laws and for asserting the right to expel aliens (Loyalists), March 24, 1784; 14-1/2x9; Commonwealth of Massachusetts
    D. 4p.,end. Copy. Attest: John Avery, jun. Sec. (see Loyalist... Material; 1782-1798.)
  - An ordinance respecting suits for the recovery of debts, March 26, 1784; 12x7-1/2; South Carolina. General assembly
    D. Attest: John Vanderhorst, sec. 3p.and end. (see Loyalist ... Material; 1782-1798.)
  - A representation of such acts passed in the United States relative to them, passed since the peace, [1784]; 14-1/2x9-1/4; Loyalists, American
    D. 13p.and end. (see Loyalist... Material; 1782-1798.)
  - Petition to the Lords commissioners of His Majesty's Treasury, [1784?]; 15-1/4x9-1/2, 15x10; Loyalist American merchants
    D.S.: Cumb[erlan]d Wilson and 36 others. 3p. (see Loyalist... Material; 1782-1798.) ----Copies (2).
  - Classes of loyalists and their claims on the British treasury, [1785?]
    Groups of claimants based on services rendered; includes "Claimants who rendered services", "Claimants who bore arms", etc.
  - Statement of monies paid to John Penn, sr., and John Penn, jr., by the state of Pennsylvania, Oct. 24, 1788; 14-1/2x9-1/4; Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796
    D.S.: Dav[i]d Rittenhouse and Jo[h]n Nicholson. 2p.and end. (see Loyalist... Material;1782-1798.) Attached to this is: Penna. Supreme executive council. Certification...; Oct. 25, 1788.
  - Certification of authenticity of statement by D.Rittenhouse and John Nicholson, Oct. 25, 1788; 8x12-3/4x; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
    Philadelphia, Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: David Redick, vice president. Attest: Cha[rle]s Biddle, Secy. 1p. Seal. (see Loyalist... Material; 1782-1798.) Attached to: D.Rittenhouse. Statement...;Oct.24, 1788.
  - Brief state of the case of the British merchants trading to North America prior to 1776, March 18, 1794; 15x9-3/4; Merchants - British
    D. 8p.and end. (see Loyalist... Material; 1782-1798.)
  - Letter to Alex[ander] Brynes, June 1, 1798; 9-1/4x8; Edward, Lt.Gen
    Halifax, L. 1p.and end. Duplicate. (see Loyalist... Material; 1782-1798.) Orders him to pay artificers from the war chest.